The truth is...
（玉来(たまらい)）あたし 本当はね—
本当は高校では もう
バレーやらないつもりだったんだ
Honestly, I wasn't going to
play volleyball in high school.
（狩生(かりう)）えっ え？
Sports have always been
the only thing I was good at.
（玉来）あたし 昔から
運動神経だけは やたらよくて—
I'd get better records in track or swimming
than kids on the teams.
陸上とか水泳も 部員より
いい記録 出しちゃって—
選考会の選手になったりして—
I'd end up qualifying for meets.
すごく… 恨まれてた
I earned a lot of resentment.
I just liked moving my body.
（玉来）ただ 運動するのが
好きなだけなのに—
But the harder I tried,
the more I hurt people.
頑張れば 頑張るほど
周りを傷つけて—
Even on the volleyball team
I joined in junior high,
中学で入ってたバレー部でも—
if I scored,
あたしが点取っても—
そんなの もう当たり前みたいな
顔されて いつも１人浮いてた
everyone acted like that was expected.
I was always left out.
Kaizaki-kun, you asked me the other day
前に海崎(かいざき)君 聞いたよね
why I didn't go to a school
with a better volleyball team.
もっとバレー強いとこ
行けたんじゃないかって
I just got sick of it in junior high,
中学で そういうの
嫌になっちゃって—
so I turned down offers from
all powerhouse teams.
強豪校の誘い
全部 断っちゃったんだ
But I still wanted to play something,
でも やっぱり部活したくて—
今度こそって気持ちで
またバレー部に見学に行って—
so I came to check out the
volleyball team, hoping against hope.
そこで玲奈(れな)と出会った
And that's where I met Rena.
〜♪
Everyone's Selfish Desires
Okay, trial first-years, that's enough.
（天津(あまつ)）じゃあ
体験入部の１年は ここまで
We're still going tomorrow,
so come hang out, if you like.
明日もやってるから
よかったら遊びに来てね
Thank you!
（生徒たち）
ありがとうございました
Thank goodness.
（玉来）よかった…
部活に力を入れてない 進学校
This is a prep school that doesn't
care about sports too much.
あたしを知っている人なんていない
Nobody knows who I am.
うまくプレーしてれば—
If I play well, I'll find good teammates
to play volleyball with.
一緒にバレーする仲間が…
できる…
Hey.
（狩生）ねえ
（玉来）あっ
（狩生）ちょっといい？
Got a sec?
You're Tamarai-san from
Toyofuji Junior High, right?
あなた—
トヨフジ中の玉来さんでしょ？
What the hell were you doing today?
何なの？ 今日のプレー
なめてるの？
Mocking us?
You don't need to work
any harder at Aoba, huh?
（狩生）青葉(あおば)だったら
この程度でいいや
みたいなこと？
（玉来）ちがっ… そんなんじゃ…
うっ…
No, that's not...!
Hit it.
（狩生）打ってきて 本気で
（玉来）え？
For real.
Just do it.
（狩生）いいから
If you hold back, I'll be pissed.
手 抜いたら 怒る
What's with this girl?
（玉来）何なの？ この子
A-Are you okay?
だ… 大丈夫ですか？
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい ホントに本気で
やっちゃいました ごめんなさい
I actually hit it with
everything I had! Sorry!
やっぱり 絶対
手 抜いてると思った
I knew it!
I knew you were holding back!
I'm Kariu Rena.
あたし 狩生玲奈
You'll join the team, right,
Tamarai Honoka-san?
バレー部 入るんでしょ？
玉来ほのかさん
これから３年間
いっぱい練習して—
For the next three years,
I'm gonna practice real hard
and get good enough to match you.
あなたと肩を並べられるくらい
絶対うまくなってやる
Got it?
よろしくね 今度 手抜いたりしたら
許さないから
Don't you dare hold back again.
（玉来）初めてライバルができて
うれしかった
It was my first time having
a rival. I was overjoyed.
If it weren't for Rena, I wouldn't have gotten
to spend three wonderful years here.
玲奈がいなかったら あたしの
この３年間は きっとなかった
すごく感謝してるんだ
I'm really grateful to her.
That's why I want to play
our last match together.
だから やっぱり
引退試合は 一緒に出たい
But Rena said she couldn't.
でも 玲奈には
無理だって言われちゃった
Not just that. I'm scared we
won't even be friends anymore.
それどころか このままじゃ—
友達でいられなく
なっちゃうんじゃないかって…
I want to talk to her...
ちゃんと 話したいんだけど—
But she might push me away again.
また 拒絶されたら
どうしようって…
I'm afraid the next time I speak
to her really will be the last.
次に声を
かけた時が—
本当に 終わりに
なっちゃうんじゃ—
ないかって…
I'm scared.
怖くて…
（日代(ひしろ)）お２人は いい友達です
You're good friends.
You should treasure that.
大事にしてほしいです
I transferred a lot as a kid.
私は 転校の多い子供でした
Hello, I'm Hishiro Chizuru!
（日代）はじめまして
日代千鶴(ちづる)です！
Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
I'd make friends, and then transfer again.
（日代）
友達ができても すぐまた転校で…
はじめまして 日代千鶴です
よろしくお願いします
Hello. I'm Hishiro Chizuru.
Nice to meet you.
I could feel my heart growing numb.
次第に心が
マヒしていくのを—
感じました
Was there any point to me being there?
自分は いる意味があるのか…
I grew convinced that
no one would even remember me.
誰の記憶にも 残らないのでは
ないかと思うようになり…
日代千鶴です
よろしくお願いします
I'm Hishiro Chizuru.
Nice to meet you.
I gave up on knowing people.
人と関わることを あきらめました
And this mess is the result.
その結果が このザマです
"This mess"?
（海崎）このザマて…
If you keep avoiding her,
you'll drift further apart,
（日代）避け続けていたら
どんどん疎遠になって—
本当に どう接したらいいのか
分からなくなってしまうんです
and you really won't know
how to talk to them.
Value the friends you have.
お友達を大切にしてください
私のように
あきらめないでください
Don't give up like I did.
The bond between you two makes me...
私は お２人の仲を とても…
Makes me...
とても…
The bond between you makes me very jealous.
お２人の仲を
とてもうらやましいと思ってました
The times you're spending now,
and the friends you have,
今しかない時間も 友達も
かけがえのないものだと思います
are irreplaceable.
Make the most of them,
or you'll regret it someday.
大切にしてください
将来 後悔しないために
Thank you, Hishiron. Kaizaki-kun.
ありがとう ひしろん
海崎君
I'll go talk to Rena.
あたし
玲奈と話してみる
I can't leave things like this.
このままは やっぱり嫌
Thanks! You've given me strength!
ありがと 勇気 出てきた
You haven't smiled like that in a while.
久々に玉来さんの笑顔を見ました
（玉来）そうかな？
Is that right?
You were quite ugly the other day.
この間は ブサイクでしたし—
（玉来）ブサイク 言わないで！
Don't say that!
Ah, sorry we kept you this long.
（海崎）ああ ごめんね 遅くまで
Okay. Let's go.
（海崎）じゃ 帰ろっか
（日代）ううう…
Crap!
（朝地(あさじ)）やばい
（犬飼(いぬかい)）隠れろ
Hide!
Hey, don't push...!
（大神(おおが)）ちょっ 狩生 押さないで
（玉来）いいよ １人で平気… あっ
Nah, I got it...
What are you doing?
何してんだ？ お前ら
（狩生）くっ
（玉来）待って 玲奈！ お願い！
Wait, Rena! Please!
Your ankle seems better.
足 大丈夫みたいだね
よかった
Good.
I really want to play in
the tournament with you.
あたし やっぱり
玲奈と大会 出たいよ
I don't want things to end like this.
玲奈とこんな最後 嫌だよ
It's my fault you got hurt,
so maybe I'm being selfish.
ケガさせといて“何を勝手に”って
思うかもしれないけど—
But please. Come back to the team.
お願い 部活に戻ってきて
Let's play together again.
また一緒に バレーしよう
I already told Amatsu-sensei.
（狩生）もう天津先生にも
言ったから
I'm gonna retire.
（狩生）このまま 引退しますって
（玉来）でもまだ…
But, you c—
（狩生）あたしの部活は
終わったの！
I'm done with the team!
（狩生）もうどうでもいいの！
（玉来）えっ…
I don't care!
Just let it drop!
（狩生）これ以上
ごちゃごちゃさせないで
Kariu-san!
（日代）狩生さん
私 大会 見に行きますから
I'm going to watch the tournament.
お２人が いつも楽しそうに
話していたバレー —
I want to see what you two always
looked so happy talking about.
見に行きますから
Tamarai-san.
（大神）玉来さん これ
言っていいか 分かんないけど…
I dunno if I should say this,
but Kariu was crying the other day.
（大神）この前 狩生 泣いてたんだ
（玉来）え？
The day after she got hurt, I think.
（大神）
たぶん ケガをした次の日…
Back then, I had no idea why she was crying.
あの時は 何で泣いているのか
全然 分かんなかったんだけど—
But I think I get it now.
今なら ちょっと分かる
If she really didn't care
about you or the club,
玉来さんのことも
部活のことも—
本当に どうでもいいって
思ってたら—
泣いたりしないと思うんだ
I don't think she'd cry.
She's so stubborn!
あの強がりな狩生がさ
So, um, I dunno how to say it...
だから その…
うまく言えないんだけど—
My point is, what she said just now
isn't how she really feels.
さっきのは きっと
本心じゃないと思うなあ なんて…
Thanks, Oga-kun.
（玉来）ありがとう 大神君
（大神）えっ
I think so, too.
あたしも そう思う
Rena really is stubborn.
玲奈 ホント 強がりだもんね
あたし 玲奈を信じて待つ
I'm gonna trust her and wait.
Sorry I couldn't
be of more help.
I was only able to talk
to Tamarai-san because
you were there. Thank you.
Tamarai-san said she'd
trust Kariu-san and wait.
I'll do the same.
Again, why use that sticker there?!
（海崎）
だから何で そこでそのスタンプ
Yeah?
（海崎）はい
（夜明(よあけ)）あ もしもし 海崎さん？
Ah, hello, Kaizaki-san?
I was wondering about
your schedule this weekend.
土日のスケジュールを
聞いておこうと 思いまして
何か 予定はありますか？
Do you have any plans?
む… 日代さんと
バレーの試合を見に行く
Going to watch volleyball
with Hishiro-san.
（夜明）えっ デートですかあ？
A date?!
しらじらしいな
Oh, come on!
どうせ知ってんだろ？ 全部
You know everything already!
This isn't for fun.
んな 明るい状況じゃねえよ
（夜明）あはは これは失礼
もちろん全部存じてます
I beg your pardon.
Of course I know.
Let's hope Kariu-san shows.
狩生さん 現れるといいですね
Thank you, Kaizaki-san.
ありがとうございます 海崎さん
は？ 何だよ 急に
Huh? Where'd that come from?
I just felt like saying thanks.
（夜明）いや ちょっと
お礼が言いたい気分だったので
訳分かんねえ 気持ち悪っ
You're not making any sense. Creepy.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow. Bye!
（夜明）では また明日 失礼します
"Thanks"?
（海崎）礼？ 何もしてねえぞ
変なやつ
I didn't do anything. Weirdo.
Wait, tomorrow?
って また明日って…
来るのかよ
He's coming?!
Honoka!
（天津）ほのか
（玉来）ん…
Is Rena...?
（天津）玲奈は…
（玉来）ううん
そう… 家にも電話したんだけど
Oh. I called her place, but...
Let's have a good match!
（選手たち）よろしくお願いします
やっぱり いねえか
I knew she wouldn't show.
で… でも
明日もあるんだよね？ 大会
But the tournament goes on tomorrow, too!
大会はあるんだけど…
The tournament does, but...
This is an elimination tournament.
トーナメント戦だからな
負ければ 明日どころか
この試合で終わりだ
If they lose, they don't play
ever again, let alone tomorrow.
Does anybody know where Kariu lives?
（日代）どなたか 狩生さんの
家を ご存知ありませんか？
（犬飼）知らねえのか？
You don't know?
Um... sorry.
（大神）ええっと ごめん
I'm done waiting.
もう待てません
引きずってでも 連れてきます
I'll drag her here if I have to.
（日代）海崎さん
（海崎）えっ？
Kaizaki-san.
知りませんか？ 狩生さんの家
Do you know where she lives?
えっ ごめん 俺は知らない
Sorry. I don't.
Kariu-san's address.
（海崎）うっ 怖っ
Yikes! It's bad enough
that he knows her address,
住所 知ってることも 怖いけど—
but to send it with this timing
is really creepy!
このタイミングで
すかさず送ってくるの 怖っ
Uh, I'll ask Sensei.
ああ えっと…
じゃあ 俺
先生に聞いてみるから—
Let's go.
（海崎）一緒に行こう
（日代）はい
Right.
Oga, keep us updated on the match.
大神 試合の状況とか
ちょくちょく連絡してくれ
G-Got it.
りょっ 了解
That's unusual.
（小野屋(おのや)）珍しいですね
先輩が 積極的に手を貸すなんて
Not like you to step in and help.
You're always yelling at me
for getting too involved.
過度な干渉はダメだって—
いつも うるさいのに
Are you that happy things are changing?
変わり始めていることが
そんなにうれしい？
Yeah.
そうだね
Kariu
Yeah?
（狩生）はい
（日代）ひし…
It's...
あ 宅配便でーす
Um, delivery.
Coming!
（狩生）はーい
She might not open if she knows it's us.
俺らって分かったら
開けてくれないかもだろ？
I see.
なるほど
息をするように ウソをつきますね
Lying comes as naturally to you as breathing.
Your character is suspect.
人格を疑います
（海崎）そこまで言う？
Did you really have to go that far?
Yo!
（海崎）よっ
（日代）こんにちは
Hello.
（海崎）くっ ここまで来て
逃がさねえぞ 狩生
We've come too far
to let you get away, Kariu.
Why are you here?
（狩生）何しに来たのよ
We all believed you would come
and waited, but you didn't.
みんな
狩生さんが来ると信じて—
待っているのに
来なかったので—
So we came to drag you there.
引きずりだしに 来ました
I never asked you to believe in me.
勝手にそんなこと
期待されても困るけど
I didn't want to go, so I didn't.
行きたくないから 行かなかった
That's all.
それだけなのに 迷惑よ こんなの
Don't show up like this.
You're dressed like you're going.
（日代）行く気マンマンの
格好に見えるんですが
これは部屋着で…
I wear this at home!
Your team tracksuit?
（日代）部活のジャージが？
（狩生）そうよ
Yes!
中に着ているそれは
ユニフォームでは？
With your uniform underneath?
You wanted to go, didn't you?
（日代）本当は—
行こうとしていたんじゃ
ないですか？
To play one last match with Tamarai-san.
玉来さんとの 最後の試合…
It's none of your business.
（狩生）関係ないでしょ
何なのよ ズカズカと
You've got a lot of nerve.
日代みたいな鈍感に—
Hishiro, you're too dense
to understand how I feel, so stop trying!
あたしの気持ちなんて
分かるわけ ないのに—
（狩生）踏み込んで来ないでよ！
（海崎）狩生！
Kariu!
If I don't understand how a friend feels,
（日代）気持ちが
分からなければ—
am I not allowed to worry about them?
友達を心配してはいけませんか？
If I don't experience what you do,
同じ目に遭っていなければ—
am I not allowed to
worry about you, my friend?
友達を心配してはいけませんか？
Please, let that iron guard
down for a minute.
頼むから 少しは
その鉄壁を崩してくれよ
損だぞ それ
It's only hurting you.
I know, when you've hit rock bottom,
確かに 自分が
どん底にいる時—
people trying to cheer you up
can be really annoying.
人からの 慰めとか優しさが
妙に痛いことって あるよな
"What would you know?"
“お前に何が分かるんだ”
"Just leave me alone."
“ほっといてくれよ”って…
But what if someone you're pushing away
でも そうやって
拒絶してる中に—
is really worried about you?
本気で心配してくれてる人が
いたら どうする？
That'd be a shame.
もったいねえだろ？
日代さん
Hishiro may be awkward,
but she was genuinely worried.
不器用なりに
すげえ心配してたんだぞ
I didn't ask her to be.
（狩生）誰も 頼んでないじゃない
そんなこと…
恩着せがましい
Quit patronizing me.
あっ 狩生！
Kariu!
Ow!
いったっ！
日代さん
きゅ 急にどうしたのかな？
Hishiro-san?
Wh-What's gotten into you?
Knock it off already, you stubborn fool.
いい加減にしなさい この頑固者
What do you want, Kariu-san?
狩生さんは どうしたいんですか？
To stay at home forever?
このまま家で
引きこもってたいですか？
３年間 頑張ってきた部活を
こんな形で 終わらせたいですか？
To throw away three years
of practice like this?
親友との関係も
終わらせたいですか？
To cut ties with your best friend?
To spend the rest of the school year all alone?
１人 淡々と 残りの学生生活を
過ごしたいですか？
I did that. I don't recommend it.
経験から言えば お勧めはしません
This moment, right here?
今のこの時に—
あとから戻ることは
できないんです
You can't come back to it.
ちゃんと試合に出て—
I want you to go to that match
and laugh with Tamarai-san again.
これからも玉来さんと
笑っていてほしいです
I want the three of us to
eat lunch together again.
また３人で—
一緒に お昼を食べたいです
I'm not trying to patronize you.
恩に着せるつもりは ありません
Just trying to fulfill my selfish desire.
これは私のわがままです
だから—
So...
...let me know your selfish desire.
狩生さんの わがままも
聞きたいです
本当に これでいいんですか？
Do you really want
things to stay this way?
本当は どうしたいんですか？
What do you actually want?
I want...
試合… 出たい…
...to play.
試合に出たい
I wanna play!
最後の…
It's the last...
今まで一緒に頑張ってきた
最後の…
We all worked so hard,
and this is the last...
But I haven't practiced for two weeks.
でも２週間も練習休んだ
こんな状態じゃ
I can't stand next to Honoka.
ほのかの隣になんて立てない
部のみんなも きっといい顔しない
My teammates won't want me there.
I can't just jump into a match
足が治ったら
すぐに試合に出るなんて—
the moment my ankle's healed!
そんな都合のいいこと 許されない
So I made up my mind to quit
and left the team.
（狩生）だったら もう
引退しようって 決心して—
部を去ったのに
引っ込みも
つかなくなって—
I couldn't back down from that
どんどん ひどいこと
言っちゃったのに
and said some horrible things, so why
are you all being so nice to me?
何で みんな
優しいのよ
諦め…
られなくなるじゃん
You won't let me give up!
何で？
Why?
Because everybody likes you.
みんな 狩生さんを
好きだからではないでしょうか
（日代）玉来さんも言ってました
Tamarai-san said she wants
to play with you, too.
一緒に試合に出たいと
けど ケガをさせてしまった
自分のわがままで—
But since she caused your sprain,
she couldn't bring herself
to ask you to grant her selfish desire.
これ以上 狩生さんを
困らせられないと
There's no problem at all.
何の問題も ありませんね
I mean, you both want to play
your last game together,
だって 最後の試合に
一緒に出たい 出てほしいって—
and we all want you to.
All of our selfish desires align.
みんなのわがまま
同じじゃないですか
行きましょう
Let's go.
引きずらなくても
走ってくれますか？
Will you run if I don't drag you?
Hello?
（大神）１セット目 取られた
完全にあっちのペース
They lost the first set!
Momentum's against them!
あっ 試合 押されてるっぽいぞ
Your team...
They're on the back foot.
（天津）玲奈！
（玉来）あっ
Rena!
ほら 行ってこい
Come on, get going.
Good luck.
（日代）頑張ってください
（狩生）えっ
狩生さん
Kariu-san.
Rena!
玲奈…
Sorry I'm late.
ごめん 遅くなって
いや… それ以外にも ごめん
And for everything else.
ホント… その…
I really...
うふ
玲奈がいないと
調子 出なくて
We couldn't play well without you!
We've all been waiting. Thanks for coming!
みんなで待ってた
来てくれてありがと
勝とう もっと長く このメンバーで
バレーが できるように
Let's win!
So we can all play together longer!
Come on, Honoka!
（狩生）もう ほのか
いい加減 泣きやんでよ
Stop crying already!
（玉来）玲奈だって…
You, too!
Why did I sit between them?
（日代）なぜ私は 真ん中に
座ってしまったんだろう
Sorry.
（玉来）ごめん
あたしが しゃんとしなくちゃって
思ってたんだけど—
I kept thinking I had to
keep it together, but I couldn't.
やっぱりダメで…
But when you came, I really wanted
to win, and rushed things.
でも 玲奈が来てくれたから—
もう 絶対勝ちたくて 焦って…
Would you have won without me?
あたしが来ないほうが
勝てたかな
えっ そんなわけないじゃん！
No way!
玲奈が来るまで どんな目で
プレーしてたか 見せてあげたいよ
You should've seen the look
on my face when you weren't here!
She looked dead.
（日代）死んでました
（玉来）ほらあっ
Hey!
仮に それで勝ってたとしても—
Even if we had won like that,
I wouldn't have been happy.
全然うれしくないし 楽しくない
It wouldn't have been fun.
うん あたしも—
Yeah, same here.
We lost, but that match was super fun.
負けちゃったけど
今日の試合 すっごい楽しかった
ほのか 進路希望は
このまま青葉大だったっけ？
Honoka, were you going to Aoba College?
Yeah.
じゃあ これで終わりじゃないね
Then we aren't done yet.
Let's play volleyball again in college!
また大学で 一緒にバレーしよ
Yeah...
Yeah!
ケガした日
ひどいこと言って ごめん
Sorry I was so mean the day I got hurt.
Thanks for not giving up on me.
見捨てないでくれて ありがと
No, I'm sorry for causing your sprain.
あたしこそ
ケガさせちゃって ごめん
Thanks for coming back.
戻ってきてくれて ありがと
（狩生･玉来）
ひしろんのおかげだよ！
It's all thanks to you, Hishiro!
ありがとう
Thanks.
Thanks, Hishiron!
ありがとう ひしろん
（狩生）うわっ 日代が
また変な笑い方してる
Hishiro's doing that creepy smile again!
（玉来）玲奈 失礼だよ
確かに不気味だけど
How mean, Rena!
It is creepy, though.
That hurts.
（日代）傷つきます
But it's a super weird smile!
All's well that ends well, huh?
（海崎）一件落着かな
（大神）だね
Yep.
We'd never seen Tama-chan look
so alive during a match, either!
俺たちも—
タマちゃんの あんな
生き生きとしたプレー
初めて見たよ
本当によかった
I'm so glad!
（犬飼）ありがとな
（大神･海崎）えっ
Thanks.
What's that look for?
（犬飼）何だ その顔
N-Nothing.
（海崎）えっ いえ…
（朝地）えっへへ
Hey! Tama-chan!
おーい タマちゃん
そろそろ次の試合 始まるよ
The next match is starting!
（狩生）あ そうだ
スコア係しないと
Oh, crap!
We've gotta keep score!
（狩生･玉来）ふふふ
（玉来）行こう 玲奈
Come on, Rena.
Later, guys!
じゃあね みんな
〜♪
NEXT EPISODE
Is that a new hair tie, Rena?
（玉来）玲奈 ヘアゴム変えた？
Oh, I forgot I borrowed it from Hishiro.
I'd better return it.
（狩生）あ 日代に
借りたままだった 返さなきゃ
（玉来）そう言えば ひしろん
いつも同じの つけてるよね
Come to think of it, Hishiron's always
wearing the same ones, huh?
（狩生）あのさ ほのか 日代に…
Say, Honoka. How about we...
A Trip to the Past
（玉来）新しいヘアゴム…
...gift Hishiro...
...some new hair ties?
（狩生･玉来）プレゼントしよっか